《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on The Flash
25年后  闪电侠仍未出现
你再也没有回来
You never come back.
你并不是被困在这了  对吗
You are not stuck here, are you?
-再见  西斯科  -再见  桑蒂
- Bye, Cisco. - Bye, Sandy.
我父亲的死亡证明
My father's death certificate.
在上面签字的法医  根本不存在
The ME who signed off on it, he doesn't exist.
-所以这份死亡证明  -是假的
- So this death certificate... - Is a fake.
你是谁  你想要什么
Who the hell are you? What do you want?
要你们所有人
For all of you
去死
to die.
这是...
What the...
我去
Damn, man.
又打了一场
Another fight?
是啊
Yeah.
对方肯定很惨
I'd hate to see the other guy.
场上见
See you on the floor.
闪 电 侠
第五季
第二集
这么说你并不是被困在这了
So you're not stuck here.
是的  我没被困
No, I'm not.
他们会逆转你体内的负超光子吗
So they will reverse tachyons in your system?
有负超光子是因为我
Were put there because of me.
你是在逗我吧
Are you kidding?
你知道我花了多少信用卡积分
You know how many credit card points I just blew just
来除掉你体内的负超光子吗
trying to get rid of your negative tachyons?
我本来可以用来去斐济度假的
I just bought a brand new spectral tachyeometer
结果却买了一个崭新的光谱转速计
when I could have my Fiji get away.
虽然已经没人会陪我去了
Not that I have anyone to go with, anymore.
我不会带你去斐济的  拉尔夫
I'm not taking you to Fiji, Ralph.
你们之前为什么不告诉我们这件事
Why didn't you guys tell us about this before?
25年后  闪电侠仍未出现
天呐
Oh, my God!
巴里再也没有回来
Barry never returns?
这就是你来这的原因
That's why you came here.
为了见你父亲
To see you father,
因为他没有抚养过你
because you were raised without him.
这又怎样
So what?
爱瑞丝
Iris.
那篇文章说你再也没有回来又怎样
So what that article says that you never come back.
说不定又有另一篇说你消失了
So what if the other one says that you vanished.
之前报道过不同事情的  是吧
I mean, it's said other things before, right?
我们之前让报道改变过
We made it say other things before.
所以无论未来怎样
So whatever the future brings
当它到来的时候  我们都会解决的
we are gonna deal with it when it gets here.
如果需要的话  我们还会改变它
And change it if we need to.
她说的有道理
She has a point.
如果有什么事是闪电小队擅长的
If there's anything Team Flash is good at,
那就是跟未来正面刚
it's handing the future its own ass and then some.
他说的没错
What he said.
看来诺拉
Well, looks like Nora's
还是需要更多的训练啊
gonna need more training after all.
好的  她饿了
Oh, okay. She's hungry.
我们要不
Yeah, why don't we,
都回尖端科研实验室碰面吧
all meet back at S.T.A.R. Labs, all right?
你先是见到了来自未来的成年女儿
Wow, first you meet your adult daughter from the future
现在又是这个
and now this.
信息量有点大
I mean, it's a lot.
是啊
Yeah.
我现在知道了为什么
Well, I guess now I know why
她一直不想离开她爸的身边
she never wants to leave her dad's side
还有她为什么
and why she...
从来都不想在我身边
never wants to be by mine.
诺拉会在某个时刻到你身边去的
Nora will reach out at some point.
诀窍是你需要让自己忙起来
The trick is you gotta keep yourself busy.
好的  谢谢老爸
Yeah. Thanks, Dad.
乔
Joe!
塞西尔  塞西尔  怎么了
Cecile? Cecile, what's wrong?
我听不到她想要什么了
I can't hear what she wants.
我什么都听不到了
I can't hear anything.
我觉得我失去了我的能力
I think I'm losing my powers.
宝贝  是我
Hey babe, it's me,
就是说一下  替我爸
just checking in, for my dad.
他...
He...
-你好啊  -嘿
- Hello there. - Hey.
-你在干嘛呢  -我在努力
- What are you doing? - I was just trying to get
把巴里的新战衣放进这个戒指里
Barry's new suit into this ring.
太小了
Oh, it's--it's tiny.
你刚刚没在看吉普赛以前的全息图吗
Yeah, you weren't watching old holograms of Gipsy.
-我为什么要那么做呢  -因为你想念她
- Why would I be doing that? - Because you miss her.
我们才碰到了一件特别的事
We just had something so special.
难道没用吗
Shouldn't it have work?
当然了  现在没那么特别了
Of course now it's not so special anymore
她还在我的脑子里盘旋不休
now she's just rattlin' around inside my head.
很遗憾这对你来说太难了
I'm sorry this is so hard for you.
但是你还想着她是正常的
But it's okay that you are still thinking about her.
我不觉得你能够理解  凯特琳
I don't think you understand, Caitlin.
我是说  她真的
I mean, she's literally...
在我的脑子里
inside my head.
我无法震波
I can't vibe.
所有我震波的东西都会连接到她
Everything I vibe connects to her.
我放音乐  就听到她的声音一直在唱
I put some music on, I hear her voice singing along.
我画我的雕像  就看到她的脸
I'm painting my figurines, I see her face
在科克船长的身体上
on Captains Kirk's body. Shh...
你闻到了吗
Do you smell that?
你当然闻不到
Of course you don't.
那是她的香水味  只有我能闻到
'Cause that's her perfume and I'm only one smelling it.
当然  你的能力在泛维数的时空
Of course. Your powers linked you guys
把你们连接起来  所以这完全说得通
over pan-dimensional spacetime, so it makes complete sense
你的震波回声仍然...
that your vibes echoes would still be...
将我们彼此互相连接
Connecting us to each other.
是的  我知道  感谢你的诊断
Yes, I know. Thank you for the diagnosis.
对不起  你不需要医生
I'm sorry. You don't need a doctor.
你需要的是朋友
You need a friend.
不好意思  我只是
I'm sorry. I'm just...
我真是一团糟
I'm a mess.
太好了  一直找你们俩呢
Oh, perfect. Been looking for you two.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
为了搞清楚是谁
I've hit a real wall trying to figure out
伪造了这份死亡证明  我总是碰壁
who forged this death certificate,
所以我在想  也许西斯科能够给这个
so I was thinking maybe Cisco could give this
一点点...
a little bit of a...
西斯科这会不在线
Cisco is not available right now.
请留言
Please leave a message.
西斯科  我是拉尔夫
Oh, hey, Cisco, it's Ralph.
希望你一切都好  请和我尽快联系
Hope you are doing well. Just get back to me.
我需要震波这个东西
I need to vibe this as soon as possible.
拜拜
Bye, bye.
拉尔夫  西斯科现在不能震波了
Ralph, Cisco can't vibe right now,
所以我们得稍后再解决这件事
so we're just gonna have to deal with this a little later.
为什么他现在不能用震波  怎么了
Why can't he vibe right now? What's going on?
因为我们需要帮助他走出情伤
Because we need to help him get over Gipsy.
就像你说的  西斯科恢复震波的能力
I mean, like you said, Cisco get his vibe back,
-我们就能破解这件案子  -拜托别管我了
- we can crack this case. - Please, stop caring about me.
拉尔夫  你一定有主意
Ralph, I mean, you don't have any ideas about
该怎么让人从情殇中恢复  对吧
how to help a man get over a heartbreak, do you?
我的天哪  别明知故问
Oh, my God, you stop it, girl.
你知道我有很多办法的
You know I have plenty.
西斯科  知不知道为什么我就是完美的人选
Cisco, you wanna know why I'm perfect guy
能让你克服心伤  重返情场
to help you get over this and get back into the game of love?
相信我  因为没有人
Because trust me, buddy, nobody, I mean nobody,
被分手的次数比我还多
has been kicked out of that more than me.
-你好呀  鲍比  -凡妮莎·詹森
- Hello, Bobby. - Vanessa Jansen.
你越狱了
You got out of the slammer.
现在  我打算
Now I'm gonna loosen up that chokehold
让这座城市的军火交易
you and that punk-ass brother of yours
摆脱你和你那讨厌的兄弟的控制
have on all the big arms deals in this city.
想得美
I don't think so.
这是什么
What the hell?
你知道  在铁山监狱待四年
Do you know what four years in Iron Heights
会让你感觉如何吗  鲍比
will do to you, Bobby?
会让你非常  非常愤怒
It makes you very, very, angry.
凡妮莎  不要这么做
Vanessa, you ain't gonna do this.
凡妮莎  求你了
Vanessa, please.
这就是莫雷蒂兄弟俩走私枪支的地方
So this is where the Moretti brothers have been running guns.
没错
Yeah.
从这些家伙手里偷东西  真是勇气可嘉
Stealing from these guys takes some cojones.
知道这些大胆的毛贼是谁吗
Any idea who our bold thieve might be?
还不知道  我也检视过了
Not yet. Made my rounds too.
目前为止只发现了莫雷蒂兄弟俩的指纹
So far the only prints belong to Bobby and Bruno Moretti.
无论是谁做的
Well, whoever did this,
他们下手很快而且是老手
they're running fast and loose.
如果我们不阻止他们的话
If we don't stop this,
许多大杀伤性武器将流入市面
a lot of high powered weapons are gonna flood the streets.
中城将沦为战争区域
Central City is gonna be a war zone.
无需为这座城市担心  朋友
Don't worry about the city, friend.
这件案子由中城警局最优秀的队员负责
CCPD's finest are on the case.
-你是  -诺拉  实习犯罪现场调查员
- And you are... - Nora, CSI intern.
-你是谁  -中城警局的队长
- Who are you? - The captain of CCPD.
大卫·辛格队长  我看过很多关于你的事迹
Captain David Singh. Oh I've read so much about you.
非常高兴能见到你
It's really nice to meet you.
你雇了个实习生啊  艾伦
You hired an intern, Allen?
我很抱歉  长官
I am very sorry, sir,
但是我需要人帮忙
but I needed help with,
处理我被停职期间累积起来的案件
the cases that accumulated while I was suspended
而且  你说过
and you said the Mayor wasn't going
市长不会出钱帮我解决
to give us any money to help solve them,
所以  我雇了一个免费的实习生
so I hired an intern to help for free.
等你回来之后  让她成为正式员工
Well, make her official when you get back.
好的
Yeah. Yeah.
我知道你觉得见到我很意外
I know you're surprised to see me
可我找到了这个警徽和这件夹克
but I found this badge and this jacket and thought,
然后我想我也是个现场调查员  我应该帮忙
"I'm a CSI too" so I should help my dad.
好吧
Right, okay.
你还是个新手  对吧
You said you were still a rookie, right?
是的  未来的犯罪现场鉴证技术
Well, yeah, but forensic sciences in the future
非常先进
is like way advance,
所以我绝对可以处理这个抢劫案件
so I can totally handle a robbery scene.
-小菜一碟  -懂了
- Like, not a prob. - Ah, got you.
-真棒  -那是什么
- That's great. - What is that?
我还没仔细检查那个
That I haven't gotten to yet.
但是看起来像是某个人的一块肉
But it looks like somebody wanted their pound of flesh.
-诺拉  -怎
- Nora, wait. - Wha--
你在干什么  你不能碰
What are you doing? You can't touch that.
你会污染证据的
You'll contaminate the evidence.
抱歉  你的意思是
Sorry, you mean you don't have
你们的现场没有设置玻色子频率域
a scene-wide modified bosonic frequency field
用来防止交叉污染吗
to avoid cross-contamination?
我觉得连这些词都还没出现呢
I don't even think we have some of those words yet.
糟糕  好吧
Oops. Well.
但是这看上去比人体组织的密度要大得多
It's just this seems way denser than human tissue.
你说得没错
Yeah, you're right, actually.
我甚至都拿不动
I can't even move this thing.
这不是一块肉  这是整个人体
This isn't a pound of flesh. This is a whole human body.
真是厉害了
That is so schway.
这件事先别告诉市长
Let's hold off in telling the Mayor about this
等我们得到更多信息再说
until we have some more info.
她还在为朗被杀事件生气
She's still be upset about the Lang homicide.
队长  这是路霸干的吗
Hey, Captain, did you mean Gridlock?
我以为他还被关在铁山监狱呢
I thought he was locked up in Iron Heights.
爱瑞丝  很高兴见到你
Iris, it's a pleasure to see you.
拜托你们能封锁犯罪现场吗
Can we secure the crime scene, please?
公开发表言论的话  我只能说无可奉告
You know I can't make a comment on the record.
好  那私底下呢
Okay, well, how about off the record?
下不为例  而且只看在你的面子上
Just once and that's it, and only because it's you.
好
Okay.
护送队负责运送罪犯
While in transport to Iron Heights
他们在前往铁山监狱途中被袭击了
the convoy was attacked.
朗被一位强大的人物杀了
Lang was killed by something strong.
-我们认为是一位超能力者  -有幸存者吗
- We think maybe a meta. - Were there any survivors?
四名警卫  现在还在医院
Four guards, they are still in the hospital.
-所以如果你听到什么  -我知道
- So if you hear anything... - Yeah, I got you.
谢谢
Thanks.
把这个收起来  还有
Put this away, and, hey.
-把手套戴上  -好
- Here, put these on. - Okay.
你的确有
You do have...
拉尔夫之书
The Book of Ralph.
没错  而且我们从拉尔夫之书中的一页开始
Yep, and we are gonna start with a page of Ralph
因为他还没有用到整本书的需要
'cause he's nowhere near ready for this whole book.
拉尔夫·德比克服情殇的二十七步骤
拉尔夫·德比
"Ralph Dibny's 27 steps
克服情殇的二十七步骤
to getting over the love of your life."
你认真的吗
Are you kidding me with this?
我们只是想帮你不要再对吉普赛念念不忘
We just want to help you get past Gipsy.
而且如果这些步骤对拉尔夫有效
And if this has worked for Ralph--
补充一句  多次有效
Multiple times I will add.
那么我觉得就值得一试
Then I think it's worth trying.
来吧  第一步是什么
Come on, what's step one?
鲨笼潜水
Shark cage diving.
-第二步呢  -自我肯定
- What's step two? - Affirmations.
好吧
Okay.
拉尔夫很善良  拉尔夫很棒
Ralphy is kind. Ralphy is great.
拉尔夫·德比克服情殇的二十七步骤
拉尔夫是个睿智的侦探
Ralphy is a brilliant detective.
兄弟  这些我都知道
Yeah, buddy, I mean, I know all that.
但是你要自我肯定的话还是用自己的名字吧
But it works a lot better if you use your name instead.
西斯科很有创意  西斯科很善良
Cisco is creative. Cisco is good.
西斯科比你们这些平凡人都要聪明
Cisco is smarter than your average bear.
这是悠季的  你抄的悠季禅语
That's Yogi's. You stole Yogi's affirmation.
是的  没错  因为这个很有效啊
Yeah, I did, 'cause it's a winner.
你看他可没抱着小熊在哭
You don't see him moping over any lady bears.
好吧  凯特琳  我改变想法了
Okay, you know what, Caitlin? I changed my mind, all right?
我不在乎吉普赛的震波
I--I don't care about the Gipsy vibes.
我自己撑过这一切就行了
I'll just muscle through them,
我们帮助你搞完你的事
let's just help you with your thing
然后就赶紧离开这里  好吗
and just get me the hell out of here, please?
不  西斯科  在罗尼和杰伊之后
No, Cisco, after Ronnie and Jay
你帮助我熬过了痛苦  现在该我帮助你了
you helped me get back past it. Now it's my turn to help you.
好吗  那么...
Okay? So...
我们没有时间去泰国找回自我
We don't have time to find ourselves in Thailand.
而我们也肯定不会一边看《情比姐妹深》
And we are certainly not watching "Beaches"
一边给对方涂脚指甲
while painting each others toes.
这可是很关键的一步
That's a really important one, though.
不过第十二步还不错
But step twelve isn't so bad.
我的卡夫卡啊
Holy Kafka.
别这样  西斯科  改变是好的
Come on, Cisco, change is good.
不不不
No, no, no.
改变是痛
Change is pain.
没有看你变成这样痛苦  伙计
It's not as painful as seeing you like this, buddy.
好吧
Fine.
随你怎么说  医生
Whatever you say, doc.
马修斯警官
Officer Matthews?
是的
Yes.
你好  我是爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦
Hi, I'm Iris West-Allen.
我是名记者  我在写威廉·朗的故事
I'm reporter, and I'm doing a story about William Lang.
-路霸  -什么
- Gridlock. - Pardon?
你叫他路霸
You call him Gridlock.
我读了你的博客  挺不错的
In your blog I've read it. It's good.
谢谢
Thanks.
我知道你是押送他前往铁山监狱途中
I understand that you were part of the convoy
被袭击的护送小队成员
that was escorting him to Iron Heights when you were attacked.
-差不多吧  -这是什么意思
- Something like that. - What do you mean?
我是说我记不起发生了什么
I mean I really don't remember what happened.
前一分钟我还在车上  然后车停了
One minute I was in my vehicle there was a pile up,
我下去看是怎么回事
I got out to see what's going on.
眼前瞬间一黑
Everything went black.
醒来后发现郎就躺在地上
Finally came to and Lang's laying there on the ground,
被打成了肉酱
beaten to a pulp.
他是被打死的吗
He was beaten to death?
先被打  然后被刀捅了
Beaten, then stabbed.
-还有其他人受伤吗  -没有
- Was anyone else hurt? - No.
小队里其他人都跟我一样是脑震荡
Everyone else on SWAT was concussed like me.
所以  郎是唯一的目标吗
So, Lang was the only target?
看起来是的
Looks like it.
谢谢你能抽出时间
Thanks for your time.
你好  抱歉  抱歉  抱歉
Oh, hi, sorry, sorry, sorry. Hey.
我只是有些太兴奋了
I just-I got a little too excited.
好了  你猜怎的
Okay, guess what?
你知道我的能力一直时有时无
You know my powers have been fading in and out.
大部分时间没有
Mostly out.
我肯定是要失去能力了
Well, I am definitely losing them.
你今天早上可还没对这事那么兴奋呢
You weren't that excited about that this morning.
对  我确实是
No. No, I was not.
但现在我兴奋是因为我有补救办法了
But I'm excited now because I have a fix.
我有补救办法了
I have a fix!
内心活动缓冲器2.0
Mental activity dampener 2.0.
2.0
2.0.
哈里改进了它  无论谁戴上它
Harry altered it so that you can hear the thoughts
你都能听到那个人的思想
of whoever is wearing it.
那我们为什么要这么做呢
And why would we wanna do that?
这样我们就可以在让詹娜戴上前确保有用
So we can make sure it works before we put it on Jenna.
亲爱的  这非常安全
Oh, honey, it's completely safe,
哈里用在他亲生女儿身上过
Harry used it on his own daughter,
这不意味着我们要用在咱们女儿身上
It doesn't mean we have to use it on ours.
好吧  亲爱的  听着
Oh, ok--okay. Honey, listen.
在孩子出生前
I have had a constant
我就一直和她有着
telepathic connection to our child
一种精神联系
since before she was born.
一直以来都是
It's been constant.
现在大部分时间她为什么哭我都不知道
Babe, now when she cries half the time I don't know why.
她是个婴儿
Look, she's an infant.
有时候你就是没法搞懂她们为什么哭
They cry and you always get to know why.
不  我不行
No, not... me.
我不明白
You don't understand.
我已经很长时间没照顾新生儿了
I haven't been the mother to a newborn in a long time.
当我怀孕的时候  宝贝  我怕极了
When I got pregnant, baby, I was so scared.
但之后我获得了能力
But then I got powers.
这能力可以...
These powers that...
让我成为一个完美的母亲
gave me a chance to be a perfect parent.
做一个配得上咱们孩子的母亲
The parent that our child deserves.
而现在能力要消失了
And now they're going away?
我怕我做不到那个水平了
I'm scared I can't live up to that.
我知道你很为难  宝贝
I know you're struggling, babe.
但是那装置
But that device...
不是解决办法
isn't the solution.
我们会找到办法的  好吗
We'll figure out, okay? -
但是
But...
交给我吧
I got it.
这些老旧的电脑
These old-timey computers
甚至比在闪电侠博物馆里的还慢
are even slower than the ones in storage at the Flash Museum.
基因检测以前可要花更长时间
DNA analysis used to take a lot longer
那可只是十年前
even just ten years ago.
那么  妈妈对于你消失这件事的反应
So, Mom took the news about you being gone
比我想象的要好得多
better than I thought she would.
没谁比爱瑞丝还坚强
Iris is as tough as they come.
你肯定也了解的
I'm sure you know that.
找到匹配的了  凡妮莎·詹森
Got a match. Vanessa Jansen.
凡妮莎·詹森
低等武器交易商
Low level weapon dealer
和东大街骷髅帮有联系
affiliated with the East Street Skulls gang.
我在监狱的时候碰到过这些人
I ran into a couple of them when I was in prison.
你进过监狱
You were in prison?
这可没记录到博物馆里
That wasn't in the museum.
骷髅帮让地狱天使
The Skulls make the Hell's Angels
看起来像是针织俱乐部  毒品交易
look like a knitting club, drug trafficking,
武装抢劫
armed robbery.
詹森常去的地方是哪里
Any places Jansen's known to frequent?
东大街汽车天堂
East Street Auto Haven.
看起来像是骷髅帮活动的门面
Looks like it's probably a front for Skull's activities.
好啊  我是时候打倒第一个反派了
Yes, time to take down my first baddie!
要通过你的允许 当然了
With your permission, of course.
咱们走吧
Let's do it.
磨蹭什么呢  你们得动作快点
What is the hold up? These you are gonna move fast.
看来我听的没错
Well, I guess, I heard right.
你有些东西想要卖掉
You got something you're selling.
太晚了  有另一个感兴趣的顾客上门了
Too late, another interested customer just showed up.
你想要买吗  布鲁诺
You're looking to buy, Bruno?
从杀我兄弟偷我藏货的悍妇那里买吗
From the broad who killed my brother and stole our stash?
你太自不量力了  凡妮莎
This is way out of your league, Vanessa.
在我坐牢之前
See, I would've agree with you...
我或许还会同意你说的
before prison.
但我出狱后就意识到...
But then I got out and it hit me...
我现在更强了  布鲁诺
I'm tougher now, Bruno.
我建立了人脉
I got connections with people
他们愿意出高价买我的武器
that would pay big money for my weapons.
但那些并不是你的武器
Except, they're not your weapons.
如我所说
Like I said...
我现在更强了
I'm tougher now.
这样  我去对付凡妮莎和那恶棍
All right, I'm gonna take Vanessa and the gangster.
你就盯着四周
Why don't you just scan the perimeter
以免她有人支援
for any back up she might have.
-我能干的可不止这点  -什么
- I can do better than that. - What?
你要干什么...
Whoa, what're you--
糟了
Crap.
抱歉  我不能让你伤害他
Sorry, I can't let you hurt him.
或是拿走这个
Or take this.
不知道我是超能力者吧
Didn't know I was a meta.
别难过  这是我的新形象
Don't feel bad, it's my new look.
-凡妮莎  -闪电侠
- Vanessa! - The Flash!
看来我要举起手来了
I guess I better put my hands up.
你觉得这要持续多久...
How long do you think it will--
我想诺拉已经没事了
I think Nora is good to go.
她连镇痛药都不需要
She didn't even need an Ibuprofen.
-你确定没事吗  -一点事都没有
- You sure you feel okay? - I'm totally okay.
我们继续干活去吧  闪电侠
Come on, let's get back to work, Flash.
好
Okay.
我们要搞清楚凡妮莎想要什么
All right, well let's figure out where Vanessa went.
如果她把武器卖给坏人  那...
If she sells those stolen weapons to the wrong people I--
西斯科  你能把卫星
Um, Cisco, were you able to get the satellite
打开了吗  西斯科
up and running? Cisco?
我们没法追踪凡妮莎
We weren't able to track Vanessa,
但我们倒是发现了一个
but we did find a scientific anomaly
从没见过的科学异常  对吧  西斯科
that we've never seen before, right, Cisco?
-汉第二个开的枪  -这完全是胡说八道
- Han shot second. - That doesn't even make sense.
拉尔夫  是你
Ralph, it's you.
不好意思要这么骗你
Sorry to lie like that, man.
-我们  需要闭路监控  -闭路监控
We just-- we need the CCTV... - CCTV, yes.
凡妮莎·詹森的浓缩空气立方密度很大
Vanessa Jansen's concentrated air squares are dense
非常大  蠢了吧唧的大
very dense, stupid dense.
只有那些相信爱情的人
The kind of dense reserved for
他们之间的密度
people who still believe--
才会那么大
in love.
我觉得西斯科是想说
I think what Cisco is trying to say
凡妮莎能控制原子的活动
is that Vanessa can manipulate the movement of atoms
将空气中的分子浓缩成立方状
to created concentrated air molecules in cube form.
分子之间的空间很紧密
The space between the molecules is so compact that...
没有足够的空间让极速者
That there isn't enough room for a speedster
振动出去
to vibrate through them.
我们要怎么称呼这个可以把空气分子
What do you call someone who can compress air molecules
压缩成固体方块的人呢
into solid blocks?
我不知道  方块吧
I don't know, Block.
看样子西斯科在吉普赛这事上过不去啊
So, I guess Cisco is still taking the Gipsy thing pretty hard?
我们正在想办法帮他
Well, we're working on it.
但是要进行到第17步才看到明显的改善
But you can't expect real progress till you hit step 17.
说的是我们安慰西斯科的办法
It's this thing we're working on with Cisco.
我们离开一会儿  你们没问题吧
You can do without us for a little while, right?
反正没有卫星  我们不知道凡妮莎在哪
I mean, we are blind without our satellite
就只能等到
so we're just gonna have to wait
凡妮莎下一步行动了
until Vanessa makes her next move anyway.
你呢  要在这留一会儿吗
What about you? Gonna hang out here for a bit?
其实  我正在找线索
Actually, I am working on a lead.
我能用你的实验室吗
Can I use your lab?
我有点事没做完
There's something I wanna follow up on.
-当然可以  -好
- Yeah, of course. - Okay.
好
Okay.
这是什么训练
Uh, what kind of training is this?
极速者需要学习物理
Well, speedsters need to know about physics,
空气动力学  轨迹公式
aerodynamics, trajectory formulas.
就你上回和詹森见面的情况来看
And after your last encounter with Jansen,
我觉得你应该从基本的学起
I think is time for you to get back to basics.
-我的训练就是数学  -没错
- My training is math? - Yeah.
我觉得就从第一章开始挺好的
I think chapter one is probably a good place to start.
你算摊上好事了
All right, you're in for a real treat.
他开始没答应  但我告诉他
He initially said no, but after I told him
你堂哥是约翰·斯塔莫斯
that your cousin was John Stamos.
我堂哥不是约翰·斯塔莫斯
My cousin is not John Stamos.
他就同意了
He agreed to you on.
向你隆重介绍我的私人造型师  布鲁斯
I proudly present my personal stylist, Bruce.
他什么都会弄  发型  化妆
This guy does it all, hair, makeup.
我穿的衣服都是他挑的
He picks everything I wear.
-那就说的通了  -来吧
- That explains that. - Come on.
布鲁斯会帮助我们完成第12步
Bruce is gonna help us accomplish step twelve.
变态
Metamorphosis.
意思是  你觉得我有点毛病吗
Does that mean you think there's something wrong with me?
就是法拉利过个一段时间也需要优化啊
Even a Ferrari needs a tune-up every once in a while.
感觉跟炼狱一样
This feels like purgatory.
你剪我头发  我就剪你
You cut my hair, I cut you.
大功告成
My work here is done.
这..
So...
我不喜欢
I hate it.
一点都不喜欢
I hate it all.
很好  那既然这事做完了
Great, now that that's over and done with.
不如我们把精力放在那张死亡证明上吧
Why don't we focus on the death certificate?
那我们得用震波感应它
Well, I mean, we need to vibe it.
或者我们可以让乔做做传统的警察工作
Or we can ask Joe to do some good old fashion police work.
你这么想过吗
Did you ever think of that?
别担心这个了  行吗
Let's not worry about it, okay?
确实是个好主意  那我们...
No, I mean, it's a good idea. We'll just ah...
我们给他打个电话
Let's give him a call.
停  我说  你们给我停下
Guys, stop. Seriously, cut it out!
行吗
Okay?
别管那张死亡证明了
Forget about the death certificate
集中精力帮我们的朋友  行吗
and let's just focus on helping our friend, okay?
我想静静
I need a break.
希格斯粒子的关键不在于数学本身
Okay, so the key with Higgs particles isn't the math per se
而在于它对其他粒子质量产生的影响
but the effect they have on the mass of other particles.
-说吧  -请问
- Yeah. - Question.
要怎么在这种粒子里面
How would one go about performing a supersonic punch
使用超音速冲拳呢
on one of those particles?
-诺拉  -爸爸  真抱歉
- Nora. - Dad, I'm sorry,
这些我都会了
but I already know all of this.
我高中课本里的物理定律
My high school textbooks had laws of physics
你们这时代还没发现呢
that this time hasn't even discover yet.
我不需要这种训练
I don't need this kind of training.
我想学习怎么变得像你一样
I need to learn how to be like you.
你觉得像我是什么意思
What do you think it means to be like me?
跑得很快  甚至能阻止一场海啸
You know, running so fast you can stop a tsunami.
或是振动比飞机还大的东西
Or vibrating something bigger than a plane.
或者是用扔闪电的方式
Or how about defeating a Sand Demon
打败了沙妖
by throwing lighting at him.
诺拉  那些事情
Nora, look, all those things
现在远远超出了的水平范围
are way behind your current skill level.
你得把你目前能做到的做好
You gotta stick to what you can handle right now.
不能因为我是你女儿
Uh, just because I'm your daughter
你就百般呵护我
doesn't mean you have to baby me.
我能做得的远不止你以为的那些
I can handle way more than you think.
看好了
Watch.
爸
Dad!
-爸  你没事吧  -没事
- Dad, are you okay? - I'm okay.
我之前也被闪电劈过
I've been hit with lighting before.
-没事  -有事
- It's okay. - It's not okay.
我想伟大是无法遗传的
I guess greatness isn't hereditary.
中城警局
中城数据库
随身摄像头视频
Body cam footage.
马修斯警官
Officer Matthews.
找到了
Bingo!
那是什么
What the hell was that?
待在那别动  别动
Stay where you are. Freeze don't move.
那是什么
What was that?
帮我个忙
Hey, I need your help.
开门见山啊
That's blunt.
对  诺拉根本没跟爱瑞丝待一起
Yeah, so Nora, isn't really spending any time with Iris.
她一直都粘着我  知道吧
So she's kind of with me all the time, you know?
我一直都在亲自训练她
And I've been training her a lot by myself
可我就是不懂
and I just don't get it.
我是说她好像
I mean, it's like--
一直在做一些暂时还力不能及的事
she keeps taking things on that she can't handle yet.
她好像为了伟大而可以逞能
It's like she wants to go big for big sake
我努力想把她拽回来  但她好像就是不听
and I try to walk her back, but it's like she's not listening
我教她的东西
to what I'm teaching her, you know?
实际上她听到的似乎总是
It's actually that she hears the opposite
与我教的相反  你点什么头
of what I'm saying. Why are you nodding?
你是认同我说的吗
Are you agreeing with me?
还记得你四年级时的科学竞赛吗
Do you remember your 4th grade science fair?
记得  但那跟我说的有什么关系
Yeah, but what does that have to do with this?
你本来只需要做一个小苏打火山
All you had to do is make a baking soda volcano.
-可你具体做了什么  -我
- And what did you do? - I...
你造了个带轮子的机器人
You built a robot with wheels,
几乎快把体育馆烧掉了
pretty much set the gym on fire.
也差点烧着仲马老师
Almost got Mrs. Dumas too.
-但这是两码事  -怎么说
- But that was different. - How so?
那是你收养我的第一年
That was the first year you took me in.
你是在我无亲无故时收养我的
I mean, you took me when I had no one.
我很崇拜你  你是我的英雄  我
I looked up to you. I mean, you were my hero. I--
我当时超想让你另眼相看
I really wanted to impress you.
巴仔  那姑娘对你的了解
Bar, all the information
全都来自那家博物馆
this girl has on you comes from that museum.
里面全都是
There're literally statues
你高高在上的雕像
of you on pedestals.
你觉得她想如何让自己的英雄另眼相看
How do you think she wants to impress her hero?
那我该怎么办
So what do I do?
让她知道一开始的时候不完美
Well, show her it's okay not to be perfect
并没什么的
coming out of the gate.
没有捷径可走
There's no shortcuts.
完善是需要时间的  并不是失败
Takes time to get things right and that's not a failure.
人生就是如此
That's life.
也要告诉她不论发生什么
And also show her that no matter what
你都会爱她
you're always gonna love her.
父母都这样
That's what parents do.
好  好  谢谢  乔
Yeah. Yeah, thanks, Joe.
回见
See you later.
这是干什么
What was that for?
情不自禁
Just 'cause.
交给我吧
I got her.
好啊  给你
Yeah, you do.
甜腻腻的糕点
Ah, yes, the sugary pastry.
我觉得如果要逃避感情
I think as far as avoiding your feelings goes,
肉桂面包是个不错的选择
cinnamon bun was a solid choice.
状态不错哦
You look nice.
是啊  布鲁斯把我的衣服都烧毁了  所以
Yeah, well, I think Bruce burned all my clothes, so...
你为什么不想查查
Why don't you want to investigate
你爸爸的死亡证明
your dad's death certificate?
因为
Because...
如果是真的
if it's true...
如果他一直都活着
if he has been alive this whole time...
那只是意味着他不想见我
It just means he didn't want to see me.
2017年九月
Sept. 2017,
承认她不是你的毕生挚爱
accept that she isn't the love of your life
因为如果是  她就不会离开
because if she were, she'd still be in it.
-对拉尔夫·德比来说太深奥了  -是啊
- Pretty deep for Ralph Dibny. - Yeah.
虽然他挥了26次才击中球
Granted it took him 26 swings before he could hit the ball.
我不知道
I don't know...
我觉得他可能会超常发挥
I think he might of knocked out of the park with that one.
吉普赛不是我的真命天女
Gypsy isn't the one.
我知道
I know that.
我也没有很多新衣服
And there's no amount of new clothes or...
或其他疯狂的变装消遣来改变事实
crazy makeover distraction that can change that fact.
因为有的真相只能隐瞒一段时间
Because some truths you can only hide for so long.
真相就是我和她之间已经无力挽回了
The truth is, it's too late for me to change things with her.
但你还来得及
But it's not too late for you.
你和你爸爸之间还来得及补救
It's not too late for you to change things with your dad.
但如果他根本不在乎我呢
But what if he doesn't want anything to do with me.
或许会这样
Maybe he doesn't.
但你不如面对事实
but wouldn't you rather face that truth
不要一辈子都在猜想
instead of spending the rest of your life wondering?
-这也是训练内容吗  -好好看看
- Is this part of my training? - Just watch.
-酷炫  是你吗  -对
- Schway, is that you? - Yeah.
我获得超能力后的头几周
A few weeks after I got my powers.
初版闪电侠  天啊  瞧你的动作
OG Flash. God, look at you move.
是啊  好戏在后头
Yeah, just wait for it.
还有这个
And this.
这个  是啊
And this. Yeah.
磨练技能是要花时间的  诺拉
It takes time to hone your skills, Nora.
你不能一步登天
You can't just can't just skip rungs on a ladder
或是直接挑大梁  这是不行的
or jump right to the big stuff. It's not how it works.
好了  我已经看够了
All right, that's enough of that.
你第一次来的时候
Look, when you first got here
你说你不是个很好的极速者
you said that you weren't a great speedster.
但很显然我一开始也不是
But obviously neither was I when I first started.
你觉得有一天我会跟你一样伟大吗
Um, do you think one day I will be great like you?
你可是打下了一颗卫星
You punched out a satellite
而那时我正全身起着火从天上往下掉呢
while I was falling to the earth and on fire.
你当时速度那么快
And you were moving so fast
就连我都看不清你是谁
even I couldn't see who you were.
-那倒是挺厉害的  -是啊
- Yeah, that was pretty epic. - Yeah.
对不起我今天没听你的话
I'm sorry I didn't listen to you today.
我只是想让你感到骄傲
I just wanted to make you proud.
有时我们这些有超能力的人
Sometimes for people with our abilities
最厉害的能力就是自我克制
the most impressive feat is restraint.
我要属于我的东西  凡妮莎
I want what's mine, Vanessa.
让开
Now step aside.
因为你这次带来了更大的枪吗
Because you brought a bigger gun this time?
不可能
Not happening.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
确定
Yeah.I'm sure.
各位  找到方块了吗
Hey, guys. Any luck with Block?
完全没找到  实验室有什么发现吗
Nothing. No. Anything at the lab?
也许吧  现在说还有点太早
Uh, maybe. It's still a little too early to tell.
752警员请求拦截可疑车辆
Unit 7-5-2 requesting a 10-61.
-那是什么  -没什么
- What is that? - Nothing.
警官请求去喝杯咖啡休息会
An officer requesting to go on a coffee break.
没有卫星简直是太难受了
Not having our satellites is killing us.
我们没法扫描城里的暗物质
I mean, we can't scan the city for dark matter
没有面部识别
we don't have facial recognition.
如果有的话  我们只要看城里
All we'd need to do is see if there any pockets
是否有压缩空气  就能找到她了
of compressed air around the city and we'd have her.
你是说像气压计一样测量大气压力吗
You mean gauging atmospheric pressure like a barometer?
但那得有一支巨大的气压计
Yeah, but it would have to be a big barometer.
你是说52波段的多普勒雷达继电器吗
You mean like channel 52 Doppler radar relay?
是啊  凡妮莎的方块
Yeah, I mean, Vanessa's blocks
是由高密度空气所组成的
are constructed of highly dense air,
所以它们的组成
so they'd have the same composition
和极端大气系统是一样的
as an extreme atmospheric system.
所以我们追踪天气  就能找到她了
So, we track the weather and we find her.
-太酷炫了  -没错
- That's so schway. - Okay, yeah.
我们开始吧
Let's do it, yeah.
韦斯特艾伦小队棒棒哒
Go Team West-Allen. Yeah!
看  在太平洋和戴维斯街周围的六个街区
Okay, look, there's a high-density low-pressure zone
有高密度低气压区域
in a six block radius around Pacific and Davies.
很好  我们走吧
Okay, cool. All right, let's go.
也许我该留在这
Hey, maybe I should just stay here.
或者你可以把训练中学到的东西运用起来
Or you could put some of that training to use.
最后一次机会  凡妮莎
Last chance, Vanessa.
最后机会做什么
To do what?
把钥匙交给我
Just give me the keys
我可以载着我的武器离开
so I can drive my weapons out of here.
快点
Come on.
乖乖地交出来
Just hand them over nice and easy.
想得美
Yeah, right.
开枪打她
Light her up!
你们俩  我发誓
You two. I swear...
她快筋疲力尽了
She's getting tired.
我们打倒她了
We got her.
是的
Yeah, we did.
抓到你了
Gotcha.
闪电侠困在方块里了
Flash is trapped!
怎么了  出什么事了
What's wrong? What's happening?
巴里有麻烦
Barry's in trouble.
她快精疲力尽了
She gets tired.
方块脑袋  试试困住我
Hey, blockhead! Try that on me!
贪多嚼不烂了吧
Bit off more than you could chew, huh?
我的活干完了
Well, my work here is done.
看来她就个普通的小方块
Looks like she's a regular chip off the ol' block.
-我是不是...  -别
- Am I-- - Don't.
我知道
Okay, yeah, I know.
送她去医院
Get her to a hospital.
XS  快去
XS! Now!
巴里  怎么了  是谁出现了
Barry? What is it? Who's there?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
我的神速力没有了
I just lost my speed.
-超能力没了  -我也没了  恶灵骑士
- I got nothing. - Negative, Ghost Rider.
各位  我知道现在是三对一
Guys, I know we're three against one,
但是我觉得这家伙占了上风
but something tells me this guy's got the advantage.
巴里
Barry!
那是什么声音
What is that sound?
天呐  巴里
Oh, my God. Barry!
巴里  马上离开那里
Barry, you got get out of there right now!
爸
Dad!
Dad.
-爸  你没事吧  -没事
- Dad, are you okay? - I'm okay.
这肯定是暗物质
I mean, this is definitely dark matter,
但这种程度的浓度
but these levels of concentration are unlike
和我之前所见到过的任何暗物质量都不一样
any dark matter levels I've ever seen before.
之前被人揍的时候
Yeah, well, that wasn't quite like any ass kicking
也不是这样的
I've ever gotten before either.
他那把匕首
That dagger he had,
我觉得会消除我们的超能力
I think that negated our powers.
他也控制着匕首  就像雷神之锤
And he control it too, like Mjolnir.
那是雷神的锤子
That's Thor's hammer.
我只是很开心你们没事
I'm just glad you guys are okay.
这还算好的了
This could've been a lot worst.
嗯
Yeah.
小心点  这些伤口很深
Careful. Those cuts are pretty deep.
可能需要一段时间才能愈合
It could take a while for them to heal.
西斯科  那些现在都不重要
Cisco, that's not important right now.
如果你想知道  现在你有机会了
Look, if you wanna know, this is your chance.
不管怎样  我都支持你  凯特琳
I support you either way, Caitlin.
抱歉  我不知道怎么回事
I'm sorry. I don't know what happened.
凯特琳  你看到什么了吗
Caitlin, did you see something?
我看到了
Yeah, I did.
我母亲
My mother.
各位
Hey, guys.
走吧
Let's go.
这下有大麻烦了
Hey, we got a big problem.
我和辛格队长说了  他说路霸
So I talked to Captain Singh and he said that Gridlock
在押送去铁山监狱的途中遇害
was killed during his transport to Iron Heights.
-路霸死了吗  -怎么死的
- Gridlock's dead? - How?
我不知道
I'm not sure.
我采访过在场的每一个人
I interviewed everyone that was there
没人知道
and no one knows.
但是我查过了
But I did some digging...
那是什么东西
What the hell is that?
不许动  别动  不许动
Stay where you are! Freeze! Don't move!
我们要找什么
Okay, so what are we looking for here?
不是找  是听
Not looking. Listening.
听着像是刚刚袭击我们的人
It sounds like the guy who just attacked us.
听着像是虫子
Sounds like an insect.
就是虫子
Yeah, it does.
-像是...  -像是蝉
- Like a... - Like a cicada.
奇卡达[蝉]是谁
Who's Cicada?